We've just received a report
the victim
has been identified
'by the San Francisco locals
as Natalie Gibecki'
although police are
keeping the nature
of her death under wraps
for the moment they were..
Her name's Natalie Gibecki.
27 years old.
Works as a counselor in a youth
probation facility nearby.
The mayor serves on the board,
so we got the call.
Petechial hemorrhaging
in the eyes
and the marks around the neck
indicate that she was strangled.
- Mmm. Where's Lisbon?
- She's with S.F.P.D.
They talked
to the victim's boss.
She was headed
to a movie with friends.
- Not likely.
- Come again?
[Jane]
'Well, she's wearing
a black lace camisole.'
She was planning on changing
her flats to heels.
Her makeup is
freshly applied.
She's wearing a very..
[sniffs]
Very flowery perfume..
'J'adore, if I'm not mistaken.'
She was going
to meet a lover.
Married, I'd guess,
based on the deception.
[cell phone ringing]
Excuse me.
[clears throat]
Hello?
'Hello, Patrick.
It's Erica Flynn.'
Erica Flynn.
Wow, this is a surprise.
Pleasant, I hope.
I bet you're wondering
why I'm calling.
Yeah. Thought crossed my mind.
What if I said
I wanted to hear you?
'I'd say you were lying.'
Not entirely.
Natalie Gibecki..
...I knew her personally.
She was a client
of my matchmaking company.
- I'm sorry for your loss.
- Thank you.
We grew very close
during our sessions together
but then you know
how that can happen.
What do you want, Erica?
Yes, I haven't said,
have I?
'No.'
I'm calling because I can
help you find her killer.
Really? What's his name?
'If you want the answer,
you know where I am.'
It was nice hearing
your voice again.
Yours, too.
- Thank you, Dennis.
- Of course, Ms. Flynn.
[Flynn]
'Helpful as always.'
- Who was that?
- Uh..
That was Erica Flynn.
She wants to help out
with the investigation.
We should fax over
the case file and get her a gun.
Getting her a gun's
a bit much, but
I think
the case file may help.
I was kidding.
[chuckles]
Yeah.
You're kidding, right?
Please tell me
you're kidding.
[theme music]
Hello, Patrick.
Erica. You look good.
Orange suits you.
I suppose I have you
to thank for my wardrobe.
I didn't kill your husband.
Neither did I.
Manslaughter. Big difference.
What is this about?
I know
who killed Natalie Gibecki.
How is that possible?
We grew close
during our sessions together.
Natalie told me things that
she didn't tell anyone else
like the fact that she was
seeing someone in secret.
Why'd she need a dating service
if she was seeing someone?
She met him
during our sessions together.
That must've been
some time ago.
Ten months..
...but Natalie was still
seeing him when she died.
- I'm sure of it.
- How?
I know true love
when I see it.
Then why the secrecy?
The man Natalie was
seeing was married.
She kept the affair
from everyone.
- Everyone except you.
- Yes.
Why are you doing this?
I cared deeply
about Natalie.
Her death is a tragedy, and her
killer should be punished.
That was a nice try.
[whispering]
Alright. I want out of here.
Temporarily, of course.
You have no idea
what this is like, Patrick
living in a cage..
...knowing I'll be
here for years.
The truth is, this may be
my last chance at freedom
while I'm young enough
to enjoy it.
I just want to go to the spa,
eat at my favorite restaurant
a few harmless indulgences
in return for helping you
catch a killer.
What if you're lying?
You once said you could
see right through me.
"Transparent as glass,"
I believe, was how you put it
so tell me,
am I lying now?
[Kimball]
'Natalie Gibecki left
the youth facility at 8:14 p.m.'
A commuter found her at 8:33
giving us a 19-minute window
for the murder.
What do we have for motive?
There's nothing missing from
the body, so robbery seems out.
No sign of sexual assault.
She'd just returned from
a 5-day trip to Puerto Vallarta.
Jane's theory
about a boyfriend?
We looked into it. Friends say
Natalie wasn't seeing anyone.
- Family?
- Only child.
- Parents died years ago.
- Alright.
Head to the youth facility,
talk to the counselors
that were working on her shifts.
Can I skip
this and work the phones?
I have an appointment
in an hour.
- Are you alright?
- Yeah, everything's fine.
It's just something
I gotta do.
- Sure. Van Pelt?
- Sure. On it.
Hi. I'm Agent Van Pelt.
This is Agent Cho from CBI.
We're here investigating
Natalie Gibecki's murder.
I don't know how we'll tell
the boys. They loved Natalie.
You guys have
any idea who did this?
We're in the
investigation's early stages.
We believe
that Natalie may have been
romantically involved
with someone.
- You know anything about that?
- No.
Yeah, no. I thought
she was single. Hey, Kevin!
'Keep that up, you'll be doing
push-ups until you puke.'
The relationship could have
been with a co-worker.
- Don't look at me.
- You didn't like her?
I didn't say that.
She just wasn't my type.
Kevin! What did I just say?
Now drop
and give me 50. Now!
Know anyone who may
have wanted to harm Natalie?
No, but...we did have
a kid go missing
from the facility
last night.
Trent didn't have
anything to do with this.
- His name was Trent?
- Trent Matthews. He's 17.
Was here for drug possession
and assault.
What time did he go missing?
I saw him at dinner,
so after 7:00.
Like I said, he didn't
have anything to do with this.
We'll need to see his file.
Keep going.
You wanna let her
out of prison?
Well, I just think
Erica could help us.
She knows details
of the victim's life.
- She may even know the killer.
- She says she does.
That she's telling
the truth about.
- Doesn't mean we need her help.
- I didn't say that.
- I said she could be useful.
- What do you think, Luther?
- I'm intrigued.
- Sir.
I think..
...it's just the kinda
innovative thinking
the CBI needs more of.
Using a convict to catch
a killer...it's synergy.
Exactly.
Sir, this isn't even
our jurisdiction.
We couldn't get her
released if we tried.
You're right,
but the warden
at Golden Valley State Prison
has already approved it.
Ms. Flynn's guaranteed
a furlough through
the rehabilitation program
that the governor instituted.
[Luther]
'Apparently,
she's a model inmate.'
She's a convicted murderer.
Convicted manslaughterer,
actually.
- Oh, well, in that case..
- So you agree?
No. She's a dangerous killer,
and she's a flight risk.
Which is why I'll be
assigning two agents
to guard her at all times.
See, Lisbon?
What could possibly go wrong?
[Jane]
'Excuse me.'
Synergy.
[exhales deeply]
[cell phone ringing]
- Hey, Cho.
- Hey.
- What's up?
- You called me.
Oh, yeah.
That's right.
I got some background
on Trent Matthews.
He was attending
Sequoia Valley High School
before he was busted
for possession and assault.
It's not far
from the facility.
- Think he might head back?
- He's alone. Family moved.
He's probably looking for
cash and a place to stay.
Might try old friends
for help.
Alright. Van Pelt
and I will get on it.
You ready?
Class is about to start.
Oh, yeah, yeah. All set.
Welcome, mommies and daddies.
My name is Atoosa
and I will be leading
your class today.
Welcome to the first step
in your amazing journey
of parenthood.
Now before we begin,
I would like each of you
to go around the room
and offer something
about yourselves.
Hi.
[chuckles]
Oh.
Would you like to start?
Sure. Um, hi.
My name is Sarah.
Welcome, Sarah.
[laughs]
Oh, hi. I'm Wayne.
Welcome, Wayne.
Um...okay, I'm 28 weeks.
Uh, this is my first child.
Wait. Our first child?
Oh, yeah.
Definitely our first.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Our first child.
Well, although "our"
might be a little misleading.
Not that
this isn't his baby.
I'm not some kinda
floozy or anything
and, gosh, not that anyone
in this room is..
[Sarah]
No, I, that is,
I just meant, um..
She meant
that we're not married.
That was it,
No. I mean, yes.
[laughs]
According
to the youth facility
Trent Matthews was
busted for possession
at this high school
three months ago.
[bell ringing]
You know, kids used
to call me "Bracey Gracie"
because I wore braces
until I was 17.
- What did people call you?
- Cho.
That's him.
[indistinct shouting]
- Hey, break it up!
- Hey!
Come on!
Get off, man!
[female #1]
'Oh, yeah!'
- 'Hey, get off, man.'
- Trent Matthews?
- 'What?'
- CBI. We need a word.
Screw your word, man.
[sighs]
You needn't look
so glum, Lisbon.
If anything happens, you're not
gonna be held responsible.
Because that's
what I'm worried about.
[whispering]
You know
why she's doing this.
To try and escape,
most likely.
Yet you're going through
with it anyway.
Are you doing this
because you need Erica's help
or because you want it?
[male #1]
'Agents, you can come in now.'
'You'll have
to sign for custody.'
Thank you.
- Hello, Patrick.
- Erica.
Inmate Erica Marie Flynn
is now in your custody.
- Take good care of her.
- Thanks.
[bell buzzing]
- Alright. Who is he?
- Who?
Natalie's killer.
Don't be cute.
I don't know his name.
It's all in my symphony files.
- Did I not make that clear?
- No, you didn't.
- Must've slipped her mind.
- Where are the files?
My lawyer's having them
sent to your offices now.
Good. Let's get this
over with. You got her?
We got her.
Ms. Flynn, I'm Agent McClay.
This is Agent Morris.
We'll be supervising you
during your furlough.
A friend owns a car company
and has offered me
transportation while I'm out.
How thoughtful.
Patrick, are you coming?
[door closes]
[door opens]
This should be fun.
[sighs]
Here's your tea.
Thanks so much.
- Oh, Ron?
- Yes, Ms. Flynn.
Would you mind getting me
some lemon for that?
Of course.
Hey, boss.
I checked that trip
Natalie took to Puerto Vallarta.
- It seems she traveled alone.
- She meet anybody there?
'I'm not sure.'
We've can't
locate her camera
but Natalie did upload
travel photos on to a web site
I'm having those
printed out now.
- Okay.
- 'Here you go, Ms. Flynn.'
What is it with this woman?
She can get men to do
whatever she wants
and I can't figure out why.
Really?
I get it.
I mean, if I were a guy.
Wow.
[Kimball]
'Assault's
a serious offense, Trent.'
[chuckles]
Man, that dude was a snitch.
That why you were
smashing his face in?
Hell, yeah. He's the reason
why I got sent to juvie.
You ran away from
the facility to get revenge?
No, man.
I left 'cause I had to.
I wasn't about
to get jacked up.
You had a beef
with another kid?
Just one of my counselors,
big dude named Danny.
Danny Vargas?
Yeah.
What happened?
I mean, well, the night
I took off, he, uh..
he and Natalie
were fighting.
I mean, for real,
you know? Um..
She-she was yelling at him like
crazy, man, all up in his face
but, uh, see, Danny..
uh, he's real hard
with us kids.
He, uh,
I mean, he pushes us..
...smacks us around
when no one's looking.
Except this time
Natalie saw it go down.
She wasn't too happy about it,
you know? I mean, the girl..
The girl started
flippin' out on him.
Did things get physical
between them?
Oh, well, it was about to
until I stepped in.
I mean, y-you can't lay
your hands on a woman.
I don't give
a damn who you are.
But, anyway, I mean,
Danny got mad
real mad
so I took off
before he could
do something about it.
You think Danny would have
hurt you in retaliation?
I know he would have.
The dude has
frickin' issues, man.
He-he should be the one
sitting here, not me.
Listen,
with all bull aside
let me tell you
something, alright?
I would never hurt
Natalie, ever.
'I got no reason to.'
I mean, she-she was
one of the only adults
who ever treated me like
a person, you know?
Yeah, I do.
Hey. You okay?
Oh. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Uh, no.
That video was..
Oh, God. It was horrible.
'I had no idea that
childbirth could be so..'
- Well, so scary.
- Oh, it wasn't that bad.
Sarah, I'm a homicide detective.
I've seen some pretty graphic
things, but that..
...nothing
prepared me for that.
How do you think I feel?
I have to go through it.
Wayne, you're gonna be
okay with this, right?
Yeah, I think so.
- Oh.
- I-I mean, yes. Y-yes.
Alright. Good. Because I..
I can't do this on my own.
I know.
[Erica on TV]
'What kinda man
you looking for?'
[Natalie on TV]
'Well, someone generous..'
'...and caring.'
Someone who puts the needs
of others before themselves.
'I want a man
I can grow old with.'
A best friend.
Problem?
This is so frustrating.
One of Natalie's
interviews is missing.
How unfortunate.
I know what you're thinking,
I had nothing to do with it.
It's not my problem
if your people misplace things.
"My people?"
Alright.
That's enough. Let's go.
- Where?
- Back to prison.
You shouldn't be out
if you can't actually help--
Well, just hang on
a second.
Just 'cause
there's a video missing
doesn't mean she can't help
find Natalie's lover, right?
Absolutely.
It's all right here.
Natalie lived for her work.
She dedicated her life
to helping others.
Her finding love
without my service
can only mean one thing..
...the man she was seeing
was a co-worker.
I tried that. No luck.
That's 'cause she wasn't working
at the facility when they met.
This was ten months ago,
remember?
You mean when she was working
at the nonprofit, Casa Encantar?
Exactly.
- Shall we?
- We shall.
Welcome to Casa Encantar.
Can I help you?
My fiance and I are looking for
a nonprofit to volunteer for.
- Let me show you around.
- Okay.
We're not usually this busy,
but we're throwing
a fund-raising event
tomorrow night.
It's actually
a release party
for a book that
our CEO has written.
Here he is now.
Hi. I'm Greg Relin. Welcome.
It's wonderful,
what you do here.
Thank you.
Since we started,
we've been lucky enough
to build six schools,
four clinics, two orphanages
throughout Mexico,
all in small rural villages
some without electricity
or running water.
- 'Mmm.'
- That's our newest orphanage.
[Greg]
'We hope to have four
more by the year end.'
Ifwe raise enough
support tomorrow night.
So Evan's told you
about our gala?
There'll be plenty
of food and drink
'even some entertainment.'
'You're both
welcome to come.'
See, see what
a difference you can make.
Thank you very much
for the invitation.
Tell me, when did you
last see Natalie Gibecki?
- I'm sorry?
- Don't be.
You said you were
looking to volunteer.
I didn't. She did, she also
said I was her fiance.
- Cheeky.
- And you are who, exactly?
I'm Patrick Jane.
I'm a consultant with the CBI.
I'm investigating
Natalie's murder.
[Jane]
'She was seeing
someone here, yes?'
Not that I know of. Evan?
- No.
- No?
Oh, of course. It's a secret,
so you wouldn't tell me anyway.
Mind if I look around,
talk to some of your employees?
- Mmm...no.
- Thank you very much.
Good luck with the book.
[Patrick]
What about him?
Handsome but dim,
like a golden retriever.
Natalie wouldn't be
interested in someone like that.
Who would she be
interested in?
Someone attractive, witty,
compassionate, 25 to 35
fit, good hair,
and a romantic at heart.
Oh, that's all?
No wonder she enlisted
the help of a professional.
Good ones are out there,
if you know where to look.
Natalie was a college girl.
She read voraciously.
She was inquisitive,
intelligent, and idealistic.
She would need to be
with somebody who was the same.
Him.
You buy me dinner
at my restaurant of choice
if I'm right.
No bet. You're right.
He's the only man
that didn't look.
[Jane]
'I'll spring for dinner'
if you can get him
to confess right now.
Ooh. Bet.
Do your thing.
- Hi.
Uh, you must be..
Uh, Richard.
Can I help you?
I'm sorry. Is this a bad time?
I can see you're upset.
What? No. No, I..
I'm-I'm fine.
Uh, bad time
for, for what?
[whispering]
It's okay.
Natalie told me all about you.
I'm sorry. Natalie?
You were having
an affair with her.
That's ridiculous.
I'm a married man.
Don't worry.
I won't tell anyone.
Natalie was
a dear friend of mine.
Her passing has been
devastating for me.
I can't begin to imagine
how you must feel right now.
There's no greater loss than
the loss of the person you love.
I didn't think
that she told anyone.
This is Richard.
There's this
great place downtown.
Sicilian chef. Mmm.
He does wonders with
fish fresh, simple.
Remarkable.
I'm suddenly hungry.
- Mmm.
- Hi, Richard.
We had an argument,
but it wasn't a big deal.
- You lied. That makes it one.
- Didn't think it was relevant.
Your shift ended at 8:00,
the same time as Natalie's.
Where'd you go after work?
- To dinner with a friend.
- Right afterwards?
Yes, about 8:30.
This friend have a name?
Jim Clark.
You don't think I did
something to her, do you?
This is insane.
I didn't kill Natalie.
What were you two
arguing about?
She disliked the way
I handled one of the kids.
Thought you were
abusing him?
I got in his face
maybe pushed him
a little bit, okay?
That's it. It wasn't abuse.
Natalie came in here all
bright-eyed and bushy-tailed
thinking she was gonna
connect with these kids
and it's a great idea,
but it doesn't work.
Sometimes getting physical
is the only thing
these animals respond to,
you understand?
Yeah, you're right.
Abusing kids
is against the law.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Good.
[Patrick]
'Okay. Thank you. Bye.'
Richard Eldridge will be
speaking with
one of my colleagues
first thing tomorrow morning.
We make a good team,
don't we?
Y-you said you had
a question.
Oh, yes. That.
Would you hate me
if I told you I was lying?
These days,
I don't get to spend
much time alone
with charming men.
Well, there's a reason for that.
So you don't kill them.
We all have our baggage.
I've been thinking about you
a lot over the past few months.
I often wonder
how things would be
had we met under
different circumstances.
Thinking about what might have
been will drive you crazy.
Much better to think about
what will happen in the future.
Erica.
I like you, Patrick.
I hope my directness doesn't
make you uncomfortable.
I know what you're doing.
What am I doing?
Seducing me to conceal
your true purpose..
...which is to escape.
Am I..
...seducing you?
No.
I'm not trying
to escape, Patrick.
In fact, you don't actually
believe I am.
No?
No.
Those agents outside the door
aren't to keep me from escaping.
They're to keep you
and I apart.
I know you have feelings
for me.
This whole escape nonsense
is just your way
of avoiding those feelings.
No, actually
I'm fairly concerned
you might try to escape.
Then ask yourself this.
If those agents weren't
outside the door right now
what would you do?
What will you do?
[intense music]
[instrumental music]
[indistinct chattering]
[Jane]
'What are these?'
Pictures Natalie Gibecki
took when she was
on vacation
in Puerto Vallarta.
I was checking to see if she met
anyone when she was down there.
- Did she?
- Doesn't look like it.
I guess I was done
with those.
Natalie and I s-started seeing
each other about a year ago.
You were having an affair.
Yes.
But I wasn't just
stringing her along.
I planned to leave my wife,
it's just..
[sighs]
You know, it's complicated.
Uh, complicated?
Because your wife's family
has millions of dollars
and you make minimum wage
at a nonprofit?
'What did Natalie think
about your being married?'
[sighs]
She was patient at first.
She knew that I was unhappy.
Recently, she got tired
of waiting.
So she broke things off.
- When was that?
- Two weeks ago.
We hardly spoke during
the entire time. I called her.
I asked her to see me.
She wouldn't.
She said she needed to get away.
Clear her head.
And is that why she went
to Puerto Vallarta?
Yes.
I just assumed that
that was the end.
Then a few days ago,
she called.
She wanted to see me.
She was going to meet you
the night she was killed?
Yes.
9 o'clock. The same little bar
we always go to.
I waited an hour.
When she didn't show,
I just..
I assumed that
she changed her mind.
I-I know that, that you're just,
you're doing your job
Agent Lisbon.
I wouldneverdo this
to Natalie.
I couldn't.
Natalie was going to meet you
the night she was killed.
A married man she was
romantically involved with
who doesn't have an alibi
for the night of her murder.
You'll forgive me
if I'm a little skeptical.
[Van Pelt]
'What about the boyfriend?'
He was gonna meet Natalie
the night she was killed.
Here's the place's name.
Talk to the bartender.
See if anybody remembers
seeing him.
Where's Erica?
Getting a mani-pedi?
- How do you know?
- Alright.
This is getting ridiculous.
Erica's served her purpose.
Time to bring her
back to prison.
- Oh, we can't do that.
- Why not?
I need her.
[indistinct chattering]
Mr. Jane, Miss Flynn.
How nice to see you.
You are here as guests?
Uh, well, not,
not exactly.
I hope there's not
some problem.
Mr. Relin didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
Erica and I
are performing tonight.
Just a little something
we've been working on.
It's all been arranged.
Um, how fantastic.
Well, let's hope.
[guests applauding]
[Jane]
Thank you.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
My name is Patrick Jane.
For tonight
and for a very good cause
let's all imagine that
this, uh, tawdry hotel ballroom
is, in fact,
the Casa Encantar.
The enchanted house.
Ladies and gentlemen,
my lovely assistant, Erica.
[guests applauding]
Erica and I
will conjure up spirits
that will awe and amaze you.
And then we will turn
that awed amazement
into cold, hard cash that will
help feed, clothe and educate
'thousands of homeless orphans.'
[guests applauding]
'As you can see,
Erica has..'
...set the stage
with four boxes.
Now in order for this
performance to work
we need four willing volunteers.
Once you're chosen, please make
your way promptly to the stage.
Don't be shy. This shouldn't
hurt one little bit.
[indistinct chattering]
A quick hand
for these brave souls.
[guests applauding]
Thank you, Erica.
Looking fetching in green.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
please pay close attention.
You're about to witness
something
that I can pretty much guarantee
you've never seen before.
[guests applauding]
You will see something clouded
in the unknown
in a world of clairvoyants
and divination.
A world of spirits.
Now I know some of you don't
believe that spirits exist.
But trust me when I tell you
they are very real.
They're here in this room
right now speaking to me
just as I am speaking to you.
And they're telling me that
one of these individuals here
'is harboring a deep,
dark secret.'
Huh? Don't believe me?
Fantastic. That gives me
the chance to prove it to you.
You, sir.
What's your name?
- Richard.
- Richard, are you here alone?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Would you step forward?
Inside one of these boxes
is an item that holds
great significance to you.
I don't know which box it's in,
and neither do you.
Am I correct?
- Correct.
- Alright, Richard.
I need you to concentrate now.
Concentrate and clear your mind
of any distractions.
I would like you to choose
two boxes.
Two boxes, either on the left
side or the right side.
Please.
Erica.
'There's two boxes left.'
I'd like you
to choose one, Richard.
Now you made your choice only
with the spirits as your guide?
Yes.
Erica, if you would open
the box, please.
Does this necklace mean
anything to you, Richard?
Yes.
Tell the audience
what it means, Richard.
[crying]
It's the necklace
that I gave to Natalie.
[Jane]
'Why did you give it to her?'
It was a symbol
of my deep and abiding..
...love..
[crying]
...for her.
[Jane]
'It's okay.'
It's okay.
[guests applauding]
'Thank you, Richard.'
If you'll make your way back
to your seat, that's okay.
Wait! The spirits are sending me
another message.
They're telling me that
someone else on this stage
has a secret.
Mr. Relin.
[guests applauding]
A crowd favorite.
You're harboring a deep,
dark secret, aren't you?
I don't think so.
Oh, really?
Well, let's check, shall we?
Step forward, please.
Clear your mind
and choose two boxes.
Erica.
Now you know the drill.
One box.
Thank you.
Now you chose this box
of your own free will, yes?
I guess so.
Erica, please do the honors.
Open the box.
Is this photograph
of any significance to you?
- No.
- Are you certain?
Well, perhaps
if you saw it bigger.
Erica?
Now do you recognize it?
It looks like the site you claim
to have built an orphanage on.
'Only there's no orphanage.'
I don't, I don't know
what you're talking about.
What about now?
'It's a photo taken a week ago.'
[guests murmuring]
'There is no orphanage, Greg.'
Only a doctored photograph
you've been passing off as real.
Everything you've said
you've done is a lie, Greg.
- You don't understand.
- Oh, but I thinktheydo.
[indistinct chattering]
You're under arrest.
Let's go.
Uh, thank you.
You've been a lovely audience.
Thank you and goodnight.
[guests shouting]
[Lisbon]
'You embezzled millions
of dollars meant for charity'
and siphoned the money
into your own pockets.
You had everybody fooled
until Natalie took that
trip to Mexico.
Natalie called me.
Said she needed to speak with me
about something important.
So I met her after work
at the subway station.
I offered her a ride.
She told me she had visited
one of the orphanages
that we built.
And she accused you
of lying.
No.
Not at first.
She trusted me.
She wanted an explanation.
But..
...I didn't have one.
What could I say?
She had the photos.
My whole world was threatened.
Everything I had built
would be gone.
[dramatic music]
[sighing]
Okay, I'm coming, Wayne.
- In here.
- Ah!
What is going on with you?
[whispering]
Take a seat.
[sighing]
- Sarah, I, uh..
- Oh!
There's something
I have to say to you.
So I've been thinking a lot
about us these last few days
and, uh..
- ...our situation.
- Our situation?
Yeah.
- Oh!
- And, uh...
...I want it to change.
Are you breaking up
with me?
The opposite.
Will you marry me?
Ah!
- Oh, no.
- No?
I don't wanna get married
like this.
Like what?
I don't want you to propose me
because I'm pregnant.
It's, it's, it's so not fair
to you or to me.
[sighs]
I don't wanna live
the rest of my life
constantly wondering
whether my husband loves me.
Oh!
Wayne, gosh,
you are...you are a great man.
No, and you are going to be
the most amazing father.
[laughing]
Really.
But, gosh, we are
just not ready for this.
[sighs]
Thank you, Patrick.
You have no idea
how much this meant to me.
You know, you didn't have
to leave the other night.
We can't have
everything we want.
Since when?
If you'll excuse me,
I'm gonna go
freshen up
before the car ride.
Don't bother.
I know about your lawyer.
Lawyer? What lawyer?
'We found him a block away'
with two suitcases, cash
and a forged passport.
[male #1]
'I'm sorry, Erica.'
I love you.
I'll wait for you.
Touching.
So it's over.
[sighing]
You can't blame a girl
for trying.
I'd expect nothing less.
[sighs]
It was nice to see you,
Patrick.
I had a lovely time.
Me, too.
Goodbye.
Well, when you say it like that,
it makes it sound like forever.
Just 15 to 20.
- Just sign here?
- Yes, sir. Bottom of the page.
Time to go, ma'am.
Of course.
[instrumental music]
[Wainright]
'Glad that all worked out.'
Yeah.
Special Agent,
Luther Wainright?
'I'm Officer Hopkins'
from Golden Valley State
Correctional Institution.
We're here to take custody
of Erica Flynn.
I'm sorry. I'm confused.
I just signed custody.
[Hopkins]
'Sir?'
The US Marshals are helping
with the search.
She's been flagged on the flight
lists and all border crossings.
You're wasting your time.
Thanks for your optimism.
I have to ask, Jane.
Did you know
Erica was gonna do this?
Try to escape?
Of course.
I mean, who wouldn't?
You didn't answer my question.
No, I didn't..
...answer your question.
[thundering]
[phone ringing]
[clears throat]
- Hello?
- 'Hello, Patrick.'
[Erica]
'I wanted to thank you
for dinner the other night.'
It was the best date
I've had in years.
It wasn't a date.
If you say so.
- 'Where are you?'
- Someplace warm.
Why? Do you miss me?
[chuckles]
Something like that.
You know, Patrick,
we'd have been good together.
Wouldbe good together.
I will find you.
It's only a matter of time.
Oh, Patrick.
I'm almost looking forward
to it.
[instrumental music]
[theme music]